Privacy Policy
==============

The Medic Portal – Privacy Policy

### 1\. TERMS OF PRIVACY POLICY

The Medic Portal Ltd (“we”, “our” or “us”), a trading name of The Career Portal Limited, is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our [Website Terms of Use](https://www.themedicportal.com/terms-conditions/) and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Legislation, including GDPR, (EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679), the data controller is The Career Portal Limited, whose registered office is 14 Waterloo Pl, St. James’s, London SW1Y 4AR.

### 2\. INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

* Identity Data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier, education, title, employer. date of birth and gender.
* Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone numbers.
* Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.
* Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.
* Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
* Profile Data includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
* Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services
* Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.

We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data could be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data will not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

### 3\. HOW IS YOUR DATA COLLECTED?

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

* **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
    * apply for our products or services;
    * create an account on our website;
    * request marketing to be sent to you;
    * fill out a form on our website;
    * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
    * give us feedback or contact us.
* **Third parties or publicly available sources.** We will receive personal data about you from various third parties as set out below:
* **Technical Data** from the following parties:

(a)        analytics providers such as Google based outside the UK; and

(b)        advertising networks Google Ads based outside the UK.

* Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Stripe based inside the UK.
* Identity and Contact Data from data brokers or aggregators such as SEMRush based outside the UK.

###   4. COOKIES

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our website. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our [Cookies Policy](https://www.themedicportal.com/cookies-policy/).

### 5.  USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

* Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
* Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
* Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

|     |     |     |
| --- | --- | --- |
| **Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest** |
| To register you as a new customer | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact | Performance of a contract with you |
| To process and deliver your order including:<br><br>(a) Manage payments, fees and charges<br><br>(b) Collect and recover money owed to us<br><br>(c) Collect information necessary for the delivery of the services relating to your order | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Financial<br><br>(d) Transaction<br><br>(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us) |
| To manage our relationship with you which will include:<br><br>(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy<br><br>(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey<br><br>(c) Contacting you about a form entry or enquiry. | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation<br><br>(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) |
| To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Usage<br><br>(e) Marketing and Communications | (a) Performance of a contract with you<br><br>(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business) |
| To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical | (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)<br><br>(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation |
| To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Profile<br><br>(d) Usage<br><br>(e) Marketing and Communications<br><br>(f) Technical | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical<br><br>(b) Usage | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy) |
| To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity<br><br>(b) Contact<br><br>(c) Technical<br><br>(d) Usage<br><br>(e) Profile<br><br>(f) Marketing and Communications | Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business) |

### 6\. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table above.

External third parties, namely:

* Service providers including but not limited Atomic Smash, FD Works, Loom Digital, MailChimp, Feefo, Hubspot, Tutor Cruncher, Xero, Metorik and IT and system administration services.
* Professional advisers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
* HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
* Credit reference agencies for the purpose of assessing your credit score where this is a condition of us entering into a contract with you.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

* to whom we may choose to sell, transfer or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.
* If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our [Website Terms of Use](https://www.themedicportal.com/terms-conditions/) or [Product Terms and Conditions](https://www.themedicportal.com/product-terms-conditions/) and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of The Medic Portal, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.
* We will share your personal data within the Dukes Education Group for reporting, safeguarding, quality control and potential referral basis (for example, to our consultancy division in respect of university applications). Personal data will also be shared with other organisations, such as insurers and organisations which conduct background checks, where necessary.

### 7\. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS

Some of our external third parties are based outside the UK so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the UK.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the UK, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:

* We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data.
* Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved for use in the UK which give personal data the same protection it has in the UK.
* Appropriate safeguards are in place in accordance with data protection laws. These safeguards include the use of the international data transfer agreement.
* The transfer is otherwise allowed under data protection laws (including where we have your consent, or the transfer is necessary for the performance of a contract with you).

Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the UK.

### 8\. DATA SECURITY

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Any payment transactions and passwords will be encrypted.  Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

### 9\. DATA RETENTION

We will only retain your personal data for as long as reasonably necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or reporting requirements. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

We may monitor, record, store and use any live video recording of our courses for training and safeguarding purposes.

### 10\. YOUR RIGHTS

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You have the right to:

* Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
* Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
* Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
* Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
* Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:
    * If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.
    * Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.
    * Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.
    * You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
* Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
* Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.themedicportal.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or The Medic Portal, 14 Waterloo Pl, St. James’s, London SW1Y 4AR.

### 11\. STATUS OF THIS POLICY AND YOUR CONSENT

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data although we will get your consent before sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

Where we refer to legitimate interest, this means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.

Where consent is required for our use of your information, by submitting your information to us you consent to our use of that information as set out in this policy; and if you disclose someone else’s information to us, you confirm that you have their consent to disclose this information to us and for us to use and disclose it in accordance with this policy.

If you provide us with your sensitive personal data (for example, your state of health or any disabilities) you expressly consent to us using that data and disclosing it to our service providers for the purpose given. If you disclose someone else’s sensitive personal data to us you confirm that you have their consent to disclose this information to us and for us to use and disclose it to the relevant service providers for the purpose given.

### 12\. OTHER WEBSITES

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

### 13\. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

We keep our privacy policy under regular review. This version was last updated on April 29, 2022.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

### 14.  CONTACT

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact us in the following ways:

Email address: [\[email protected\]](https://www.themedicportal.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Postal address: The Medic Portal, 14 Waterloo Pl, St. James’s, London SW1Y 4AR

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK regulator for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
